ALUN CENNYTH STOKES

McMaster University, Hamilton, ON stokea1@mcmaster.ca +1 (647) - 287 - 2418

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My interests lie in computing and mathematics, particularly number theory and symbolic algebra. I am currently interested in dessins d'enfants and the computation of their Belyi maps. I write software for high-performance and distributed computing and have substantial experience in various machine learning techniques.

EDUCATION

Master of Science (Pure Mathematics)

September 2021 - April 2023

McMaster University

Supervisor: Dr Cameron Franc

Bachelor of Integrated Science (Mathematics & Statistics) September 2017 - June 2021 McMaster University Honours: summa cum laude (10.8/12 cGPA)

Supervisor: Dr Cameron Franc The Search for Self-Contained Numbers

Turner Fenton Secondary School International Baccalaureate Program

September 2013 - June 2017

97% cGPA

PUBLICATIONS

- [1] Stokes, A. Hum, W., Zaslavsky, J. STEM Fellowship Journal. 6(1): 1-5. Available at A Minimal-Input Multilayer Perceptron for Predicting Drug-Drug Interactions.
- [2] *Stokes, A. Automatically Solving Square-Piece Jigsaw Puzzles using Convolutional Neural Networks with Gradient Boosted Decision Trees. The Undergraduate Journal. (12th edition). Accessible at: Automatically Solving Square-Piece Jigsaw Puzzles.
- A. The search for self-contained numbers: k-special 3-smooth representations and the Collatz conjecture. MacSphere, 2021, [Online]. Available at: The search for self-contained numbers.

Entries marked with † have **not** been peer-reviewed.

GRANTS AND AWARDS

Ontario Graduate Scholarship

\$15,000

May 2022 - April 2023 Competitive

NSERC USRA

\$8,120

May 2021 - August 2021 Competitive

Dean's Honour List

Awarded all 4 years of undergraduate degree

September 2017 - April 2021 Non-competitive

Global Undergraduate Awards

1st place for computer science in North America

September 2020 Competitive

May 2020

McMaster Stewart Award

\$3.750 Competitive

CANDEV Data Challenge January 2020

 1^{st} place Competitive

STEM Fellowship Big Data Competition July 2019

\$3,000 Competitive

McMaster President's Award September 2017

\$2,500 Non-competitive

TEACHING ASSISTANTSHIPS

McMaster University January 2022 - April 2022

Graduate Topics in Risk Management MFM 763 Introductory Number Theory MATH 3H03

McMaster University September 2021 - December 2021

Numerical Linear Algebra MATH 3NA3 Linear Algebra I MATH 1B03

McMaster University January 2021 - April 2021

Introduction to Discrete Mathematics CS 1DM3

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant May 2021 - August 2021

Dr Cameron Franc McMaster University

Investigated machine learning strategies to discriminate non-congruence finite-index subgroups of the modular group and compute Belyi maps corresponding to dessins d'enfants.

Data Scientist June 2020 - August 2020

Statistics Canada Consumer Prices Division

Developed NLP methods for hierarchical data structure mapping to aid in calculating the consumer price index.

Research Assistant May 2020 - July 2020

Dr George Dragomir, Dr Andy Nicas McMaster University

Building on work by Dragomir and Nicas, we investigated how quasi-hyperbolicity could be exploited to reduce roughness and distortion in quasi-isometric graph embeddings.

Research Assistant May 2019 - May 2020

Dr Ned Nedialkov McMaster University

Developed convolutional neural networks to segment photoacoustic breast images for a group from Western University developing a hand-held *in-situ* scanner.

TALKS AND SEMINARS

[†]Algebra and Algebraic Geometry Seminar

November 2021

McMaster University An Introduction to Belyi Maps

Gave a 30-minute presentation on dessins d'enfants, their relevance, and pertinent computational techniques used in my research open to McMaster's math faculty and graduate students.

Synopsis 2021 April 2021

McMaster University

k-special 3-smooth Representations and the Collatz Conjecture

A 15-minute expository talk on a formulation of the Collatz conjecture by a family of Diophantine equations and a conjecturally sparse set of numbers that are 'almost' solutions.

CANDEV January 2020

Government of Canada

Using Transformer-based Embeddings to Identify Course Redundancies

Gave a short talk on our use of transfer-learning with a transformer model to cluster courses offered by the Canadian School of Public Service and identify redundancies in course offerings.

[†]Undergraduate Big Data Competition

July 2019

STEM Fellowship

Predicting Drug-Drug Interactions Without Knowledge of Drug Structure

This was a talk given with coauthors on our method of using machine learning to predict *in-vivo* drug-drug interactions using only analytical chemical properties. This was held at York University.

Synopsis 2019 April 2019

McMaster University

Prime Distribution by Linear Flow on the Torus

A 15 minute expository talk on the primary findings of a 4-month project investigating prime distributions over non-intersecting curves on closed surfaces.

Entries marked with † are invited talks.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages[†] Python, Julia, Java, MATLAB, C/C++, CUDA, JavaScript,

SQL, PHP, Mathematica

Major Libraries[†] SageMath, Pytorch, HomotopyContinuation.jl, Macuaulay2

Software & Tools LATEX, Git, MySQL

Operating Systems[†] GNU/Linux (Ubuntu, primarily), MacOS, Windows

OTHER PROJECTS

Global Undergraduate Awards

September 2021

Dr Ned Nedialkov

Fully Automated Jigsaw Puzzle Solving by Hybrid ML

Won first place in North America for a paper on hybrid machine learning techniques to solve squarepiece jigsaws; state-of-the-art matching accuracy was reported.

National Big Data Competition

June 2020

Dr Yasaman Amannejad

Medication Recommendation by Matrix Factorization

Devised a matrix factorization-based recommender system to predict effective drugs for treating several mental illnesses, given a patient's history with other drugs.

REFERENCES

Are available upon request, preferably made to stokeal@mcmaster.ca.

[†]Listed in order of proficiency **Bolding** indicates preferntiality